Guide to the Department of Education, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Education, Yale University, records
1905-1991
RU 271
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
46.75
The records consist of administrative files, correspondence, catalogs, minutes, graduate student files, curricula, and printed material documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Department of Education, which no longer exists as a separate academic unit. Included are materials concerning the Summer Seminar in Education (formerly called the Education Conference), and the Yale-Fairfield Study of Elementary Teaching.
Yale University. Dept. of Education
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of administrative files, correspondence, catalogs, minutes, graduate student files, curricula, and printed material documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Department of Education, which no longer exists as a separate academic unit. Included are materials concerning the Summer Seminar in Education (formerly called the Education Conference), and the Yale-Fairfield Study of Elementary Teaching.
Education -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Dept. of Education; Yale-Fairfield Study of Elementary Teaching
- Records of summer seminars and courses, 1905-1907, 1931-1934; Accession 1934-A-001
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Summer School and Extension Courses, 1905-1907 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Summer Seminar in Education (formerly called Education Conference), 1931-1934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Records, 1920-1961; Accession 1961-A-001
  - Correspondence, 1920-1961; Series I
    - General, 1920-1928
      - A - Al (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Am - Az (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Appointments, Bureau of (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Ba (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Ballou, Frank H (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Be (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Beckert, W. F. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Bennington College (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Bigelow, L. H., Jr. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Bi (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Bl (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Bo (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Bode, Boyd H. (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Boothby, Ralph E. (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Boy Scouts of America (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Br (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Br (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Brook, Arthur H. (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Brook, Arthur H. (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Brook, Arthur H. (Box 3, Folder 20 - 24)
      - Bruce Publishing Co. (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Bu (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Budget (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - Bureau of Appointments (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - By (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Ca (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Ce (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Ch (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - Ch (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - Chamber of Commerce (Box 4, Folder 34)
      - Chronicles of America (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - Cl (Box 4, Folder 36)
      - Clark, Harold S. (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - Clerk, F. E. (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - Co (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - Co (Box 5, Folder 40)
      - Columbia University (Box 5, Folder 41)
      - Corwin, Margaret T. (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - Counts, G. S. (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - Course Inquiries (Box 5, Folder 45)
      - Course of Study pamphlet (Box 5, Folder 46)
      - Cr (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - Cross, Hilbur L. (Box 5, Folder 48)
      - Cu (Box 6, Folder 49)
      - Da (Box 6, Folder 50)
      - Day, George Parmly (Box 6, Folder 51)
      - De (Box 6, Folder 52)
      - Di (Box 6, Folder 53)
      - Do -Dr (Box 6, Folder 54)
      - Du (Box 6, Folder 55)
      - Dw (Box 6, Folder 56)
      - Ea -El (Box 6, Folder 57)
      - Educational Course information requests (Box 6, Folder 58)
      - Educational materials requested (Box 7, Folder 59)
      - Em -Ez (Box 7, Folder 60)
      - Extension course (Box 7, Folder 61 - 62)
        - Miscellaneous inquiries (Box 7, Folder 63)
        - Inquiries about instructors for (Box 7, Folder 64)
      - Fa (Box 7, Folder 65)
      - Fe -Fi (Box 8, Folder 66)
      - Fl (Box 8, Folder 67)
      - Fo -Fu (Box 8, Folder 68)
      - Ga -Gi (Box 8, Folder 69)
      - Gage, Brownell (Box 8, Folder 70 - 71)
      - Gl -Go (Box 8, Folder 72)
      - Gr (Box 8, Folder 73)
      - Graduate School (Box 9, Folder 74 - 78)
      - Ha (Box 9, Folder 79)
      - Hadley, Arthur (President) (Box 9, Folder 80)
      - Harvard-Yale Dinner, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 81)
      - Harvard-Yale Retreat (Box 9, Folder 82)
      - He (Box 9, Folder 83)
      - Henmon, V. A. C. (Box 10, Folder 84)
      - Hi (Box 10, Folder 85)
      - Ho (Box 10, Folder 86)
      - Holmes, Henry W. (Box 10, Folder 87)
      - Hu (Box 10, Folder 89)
      - Hy (Box 10, Folder 90)
      - In -Ir (Box 10, Folder 91)
      - Independent education (Box 10, Folder 92)
      - Inquiries -Spaulding Seminar (Box 10, Folder 93)
      - Inquiries Teaching positions (Box 10, Folder 94)
      - Interview requests (Box 10, Folder 95)
      - Irion, T. W. H. (Box 10, Folder 96)
      - Ja (Box 10, Folder 97)
      - Je (Box 10, Folder 98)
      - Jessup, Walter A. (Box 10, Folder 99)
      - Jo (Box 11, Folder 100)
      - Johnson, Leslie O. (Box 11, Folder 101)
      - Jones, R. G. (Box 11, Folder 102)
      - Ju (Box 11, Folder 103)
      - Ka (Box 11, Folder 104)
      - Ke (Box 11, Folder 105)
      - Ki (Box 11, Folder 106)
      - Kl (Box 11, Folder 107)
      - Kn (Box 11, Folder 108)
      - Ko (Box 11, Folder 109)
      - Ku (Box 11, Folder 110)
      - Kratzer, John W. (Box 11, Folder 111)
      - La (Box 11, Folder 112)
      - Laidlow Brothers (Box 11, Folder 113)
      - Lawrence Academ~ (Box 12, Folder 114)
      - Le (Box 12, Folder 115)
      - Lee, Frances (Box 12, Folder 116)
      - Li (Box 12, Folder 117)
      - Li, Chen-nan (Box 12, Folder 118)
      - Library (Box 12, Folder 119)
      - Lo (Box 12, Folder 120)
      - Locke, Bessie (Box 12, Folder 121)
      - Lord, Daisy (Box 13, Folder 122)
      - Lu (Box 13, Folder 123)
      - Ma (Box 13, Folder 124)
      - Mc (Box 13, Folder 125)
      - McCornack, Walter R. (Box 13, Folder 126)
      - McGuinness, Anna E. (Box 13, Folder 127)
      - Me (Box 13, Folder 129)
      - Meredith, A. B. (Box 13, Folder 130)
      - Mi (Box 13, Folder 131)
      - Miller, Clyde R. (Box 14, Folder 132)
      - Minutes, Department of Education (Box 14, Folder 133)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 14, Folder 134 - 137)
      - Mo (Box 14, Folder 138)
      - Mo (Box 15, Folder 139)
      - Monroe, Halter (Box 15, Folder 140)
      - Moore, Olive (Box 15, Folder 141)
      - Morning of America Conference (Box 15, Folder 142)
      - Mosher, Raymond M. (Box 15, Folder 143)
      - Mu (Box 15, Folder 144)
      - Mueller, A. D. (Box 15, Folder 145)
      - My (Box 15, Folder 146)
      - Na (Box 15, Folder 147)
      - National Association of Manufacturers (Box 15, Folder 148)
      - National Economic League (Box 15, Folder 149)
      - National Education Association (Box 16, Folder 150)
      - National Junior Personnel Service (Box 16, Folder 151)
      - National University Extension Association (Box 16, Folder 152)
      - Ne (Box 16, Folder 153)
      - New Bedford Public Schools Study (Box 16, Folder 154)
      - Newson and.Co. New York City School Survey Advisory Committee (Box 16, Folder 155)
      - Ni (Box 16, Folder 156)
      - No (Box 16, Folder 157)
      - Oa -Ol (Box 16, Folder 158)
      - Ok -Oz (Box 16, Folder 159)
      - Pa (Box 17, Folder 160)
      - Pageant of America (Box 17, Folder 161)
      - Paine, Olive (Box 17, Folder 162)
      - Patey, Phillip H. (Box 17, Folder 163)
      - Pe (Box 17, Folder 164)
      - Penniman, James H. (Box 17, Folder 165)
      - Pf -Ph (Box 17, Folder 166)
      - Pi (Box 17, Folder 167)
      - Po (Box 17, Folder 168)
      - Position inquiries (Box 17, Folder 169)
      - Pr (Box 18, Folder 170)
      - President's Office (Box 18, Folder 171)
      - Provost's Office (Box 18, Folder 172 - 175)
      - Pu (Box 18, Folder 176)
      - Public Schools -lists of Principals (Box 18, Folder 177)
      - Publicity (Box 19, Folder 178)
      - Q (Box 19, Folder 179)
      - Questionnaire responses (Box 19, Folder 180)
      - Ra -Ree (Box 19, Folder 181)
      - Rei -Rey (Box 19, Folder 182)
      - Rh - Rag (Box 19, Folder 183)
      - Roh - Ry (Box 19, Folder 184)
      - Sa (Box 19, Folder 185)
      - Sch -Sci (Box 19, Folder 186)
      - Sea -Scr (Box 20, Folder 187)
      - Sea (Box 20, Folder 188)
      - Secretary's Office (Box 20, Folder 189 - 190)
      - Sed - She (Box 20, Folder 191)
      - Service Bureau (Box 20, Folder 192)
      - Shedd, Clarence (Box 20, Folder 193)
      - Shi - Shu (Box 20, Folder 194)
      - Si (Box 20, Folder 195)
      - Sk -Sma (Box 21, Folder 196)
      - Smith, A. -Smith, L. (Box 21, Folder 197)
      - Smith, M. - Smith, W (Box 21, Folder 198)
      - Sn - Sp (Box 21, Folder 199)
      - Spaulding, Frank E. (Box 21, Folder 201 - 202)
      - Sta- Ste (Box 21, Folder 203)
      - State Board of Education (Box 22, Folder 204 - 205)
      - Stephenson, Nathaniel W (Box 22, Folder 206)
      - Sti -Stu (Box 22, Folder 207)
      - Su-Sw (Box 22, Folder 208)
      - Suhrie, Ambrose L. (Box 22, Folder 209)
      - Ta -Tha (Box 23, Folder 210)
      - Thomas (Box 23, Folder 211)
      - Thompson (Box 23, Folder 212)
      - Thor - Ti (Box 23, Folder 213)
      - To - Tu (Box 23, Folder 214)
      - Teaching statistics (Box 23, Folder 215)
      - Treasurer's Office (Box 23, Folder 216)
      - U (Box 23, Folder 217)
      - U.S. Bureau of Education (Box 23, Folder 218)
      - V (Box 23, Folder 219)
      - Wa - Wal (Box 24, Folder 220)
      - Wm - Wav (Box 24, Folder 221)
      - We (Box 24, Folder 222)
      - Weig1e, Luther A. (Box 24, Folder 223)
      - Western Reserve Academy (Box 24, Folder 224)
      - Wh (Box 24, Folder 225)
      - Wi -Wil (Box 24, Folder 226)
      - Wilson (Box 24, Folder 227)
      - Win - Wit (Box 25, Folder 228)
      - Wo (Box 25, Folder 229)
      - World Book Co. (Box 25, Folder 230)
      - Wr - Wy (Box 25, Folder 231)
      - Yale (Box 25, Folder 232)
      - Ya - Ym (Box 25, Folder 233)
      - Zi - Zy (Box 25, Folder 234)
    - Graduate Students, 1928-1954
      - A -Ag (Box 26, Folder 235)
      - B -Ban (Box 26, Folder 236)
      - Al-An (Box 26, Folder 237)
      - Ao -Ay (Box 27, Folder 238)
      - Bar -Bax (Box 27, Folder 239)
      - Be (Box 27, Folder 240)
      - Bi -Bo (Box 27, Folder 241)
      - Br - Brown (Box 28, Folder 242)
      - Brownell (Box 28, Folder 243 - 244)
      - Bru -Bry (Box 28, Folder 245 - 246)
      - Bu (Box 28, Folder 247)
      - Bur (Box 29, Folder 248)
      - C - Cam (Box 29, Folder 249)
      - Car -Carv (Box 29, Folder 250)
      - Cas -Cav (Box 29, Folder 251)
      - Ch - Ci (Box 29, Folder 252)
      - Cl - C1e (Box 30, Folder 253)
      - Co -Conr (Box 30, Folder 254)
      - Cont --Coy (Box 30, Folder 255)
      - Cr -Cru (Box 30, Folder 256)
      - Cummings (Box 31, Folder 257)
      - Cummins (Box 31, Folder 258)
      - D - Daw (Box 31, Folder 259)
      - De -Di (Box 31, Folder 260)
      - Do -Dw (Box 32, Folder 261)
      - E -E1 (Box 32, Folder 262)
      - E (Box 32, Folder 263)
      - F -Fay (Box 32, Folder 264)
      - Fe (Box 33, Folder 265)
      - Fi -Fis (Box 33, Folder 266)
      - Fit -Fitz (Box 33, Folder 267)
      - Fl (Box 33, Folder 268)
      - Fo (Box 33, Folder 269)
      - Fr - Fre (Box 33, Folder 270)
      - Fri -Fu (Box 34, Folder 271)
      - G - Gat (Box 34, Folder 272)
      - Ge -Go (Box 34, Folder 273)
      - Gr -Gre (Box 35, Folder 274)
      - Gri -Gw (Box 35, Folder 275)
      - H -Ham (Box 35, Folder 276)
      - Han -Harr (Box 35, Folder 277)
      - Harri -Haz (Box 36, Folder 278)
      - He -Hew (Box 36, Folder 279)
      - Hi -Hit (Box 36, Folder 280)
      - Ho -Hol (Box 36, Folder 281)
      - Hom -Hor (Box 37, Folder 282)
      - Hot -Hoy (Box 37, Folder 283)
      - Huden (Box 37, Folder 284)
      - Hug (Box 38, Folder 285)
      - I (Box 38, Folder 286)
      - Ja (Box 38, Folder 287)
      - Ja (Box 38, Folder 288)
      - Je (Box 38, Folder 289)
      - Jo - Joh (Box 39, Folder 290)
      - Jol - Jou (Box 39, Folder 291)
      - K - Kel (Box 39, Folder 292)
      - Ken - Keu (Box 39, Folder 293)
      - Ki - Kl (Box 39, Folder 294)
      - Kneller (Box 40, Folder 295)
      - Knep - Kni (Box 40, Folder 296)
      - Ko - Ku (Box 40, Folder 297)
      - L - Lal (Box 40, Folder 298)
      - Lan - Lar (Box 40, Folder 299)
      - Lea - Lei (Box 41, Folder 300)
      - Leith - Lew (Box 41, Folder 301)
      - Li (Box 41, Folder 302)
      - Ll - Ly (Box 41, Folder 303)
      - Mac, Mc: A-D (Box 41, Folder 304)
      - Mac, Mc: G - I (Box 42, Folder 305)
      - Mac, Mc: K - T (Box 42, Folder 306)
      - Mac - Mah (Box 42, Folder 307)
      - Mal (Box 42, Folder 308)
      - Man (Box 42, Folder 309)
      - Mar - Max (Box 43, Folder 310)
      - Me -Mer (Box 43, Folder 311)
      - Mi -Hil (Box 43, Folder 312)
      - Mill (Box 43, Folder 313)
      - Mo - Moo (Box 43, Folder 314)
      - Mor - Moy (Box 43, Folder 315)
      - Mu (Box 44, Folder 316)
      - N (Box 44, Folder 317)
      - O (Box 44, Folder 318)
      - P-Pay (Box 45, Folder 319)
      - Pe - Pi (Box 45, Folder 320)
      - Po (Box 45, Folder 321)
      - Pr - Pu (Box 45, Folder 322)
      - R- Rei (Box 45, Folder 323)
      - Rei -Rey (Box 46, Folder 324)
      - Rh - Ri (Box 46, Folder 325)
      - Ro (Box 46, Folder 326)
      - Ru-Ry (Box 46, Folder 327)
      - S -Sav (Box 47, Folder 328)
      - Sch (Box 47, Folder 329)
      - Sco -Scr (Box 47, Folder 330)
      - Se (Box 47, Folder 331)
      - Sha -Shea (Box 47, Folder 332)
      - Shee - Sher (Box 48, Folder 333)
      - Sh -Si (Box 48, Folder 334)
      - Sm -So (Box 48, Folder 335)
      - Sp -Str (Box 48, Folder 336)
      - Stu -Stw (Box 49, Folder 337)
      - T -Th (Box 49, Folder 338)
      - Ti -Tr (Box 49, Folder 339)
      - Tu -Ty (Box 49, Folder 340)
      - U -Va (Box 49, Folder 341)
      - Van K1eek (Box 50, Folder 342 - 343)
      - Vir -Vr (Box 50, Folder 344)
      - W-Wal (Box 50, Folder 345)
      - War (Box 50, Folder 346)
      - Wat -Whe (Box 51, Folder 347)
      - Whi (Box 51, Folder 348)
      - Wins -Win (Box 51, Folder 350)
      - Wis -Wo (Box 52, Folder 351)
      - Wr -Wy (Box 52, Folder 352)
      - y (Box 52, Folder 353)
      - z (Box 52, Folder 354)
      - Graduate Record Examination (Box 52, Folder 355)
      - Graduate Record Examination (Box 53, Folder 356 - 357)
    - Subject Files, 1921-1961
      - Annual Reports, 1951-1957 (Box 54, Folder 358)
      - Brubacher, J. S., 1954-1960 (Box 54, Folder 359)
      - Dingle, Hazel, 1958-1961 (Box 54, Folder 360)
      - Education Directory: Counties & cities, 1952-1953 (Box 54, Folder 361)
      - Eurich, Alvin C., 1955-1960 (Box 54, Folder 362 - 363)
      - Furniss, E. S., 1953-1957 (Box 54, Folder 364)
      - Griswold, A. Whitney, 1954 (Box 54, Folder 365)
      - Invoices: supplies &utilities, 1957-1960 (Box 54, Folder 366)
      - Miscellaneous, 1955-1960 (Box 54, Folder 367)
      - Ph.D and M.A. lists, 1921-1958 (Box 55, Folder 368)
      - Post-doctoral Seminar, 1957-1962 (Box 55, Folder 369 - 371)
      - Registrar, 1961-1965 (Box 55, Folder 372)
      - Requests for volunteer report, 1960 (Box 56, Folder 373)
      - Requests for Yale-Fairfield Study report and abridgement, 1956-1960 (Box 56, Folder 374 - 375)
      - Simpson, Hartley, 1953-1956 (Box 56, Folder 376)
      - Spaulding Lectures, 1954-1957 (Box 56, Folder 377)
      - Student lists and grades Teacher'Assistant mailing list, 1941-1960 (Box 56, Folder 378)
      - Teacher placement, 1954-1955 (Box 57, Folder 379)
      - Tilton, J. Warren, 1953-1961 (Box 57, Folder 380 - 385)
      - Yale-Fairfield Study
        - A -L, 1954-1960 (Box 57, Folder 386 - 394)
        - N -Z, 1954-1960 (Box 58, Folder 395 - 399)
        - Financial statements, 1953-1960 (Box 58, Folder 400)
        - Inquiries-, 1953-1954 (Box 58, Folder 401)
        - Progress reports, 1954-1958 (Box 58, Folder 402)
        - Requests for Teacher Preparation for Mothers who are College Graduates, 1959-1960 (Box 58, Folder 403)
    - J. Warren Tilton Files, 1929-1953
      - 1929-39 (Box 59, Folder 404 - 414)
      - 1939-1953 (Box 60, Folder 415 - 424)
    - General, 1935-1953
      - A -Al (Box 61, Folder 425)
      - Al -Am (Box 61, Folder 426)
      - American Council on Education: Problems and Committee plans (Box 61, Folder 427)
      - An -Ar (Box 61, Folder 428)
      - As -Ay (Box 61, Folder 429)
      - Ba (Box 61, Folder 430)
      - Be -Bl (Box 62, Folder 431)
      - Br -Bri (Box 62, Folder 432)
      - Bo (Box 62, Folder 433)
      - Bru -By (Box 62, Folder 434)
      - Bro (Box 63, Folder 435)
      - Brubacher, John S. (Box 63, Folder 436)
      - C -Ce (Box 63, Folder 437)
      - Ch-Ci (Box 63, Folder 438)
      - Cl (Box 63, Folder 439)
      - Co -Con (Box 64, Folder 440)
      - Connnittee on ProblemsÂ· and Plans for Integration of Graduate Work " (Box 64, Folder 441)
      - Commission on the Reorganization of State Departments (Box 64, Folder 442)
      - Conger, N. (Box 64, Folder 443)
      - Coo -Cox (Box 64, Folder 444)
      - Cr (Box 64, Folder 445)
      - Day (Box 65, Folder 446)
      - D -Daw (Box 65, Folder 447)
      - De -Deu (Box 65, Folder 448)
      - Department of Education (Box 65, Folder 449)
      - Dev -Dl (Box 65, Folder 450)
      - Do -Dou (Box 65, Folder 451)
      - Dmv -Dy (Box 66, Folder 452)
      - E -Ed (Box 66, Folder 453)
      - Education Planning (Box 66, Folder 454)
      - Ee -Em (Box 66, Folder 455)
      - En -Ey (Box 66, Folder 456)
      - F -FI (Box 66, Folder 457)
      - FI -Fo (Box 66, Folder 458)
      - Fow -Fu (Box 67, Folder 459)
      - G -Geo (Box 67, Folder 460)
      - Gambrill, Bessie Lee (Box 67, Folder 461)
      - Ges -Gl (Box 67, Folder 462)
      - Glen Ridge Survey (Box 67, Folder 463)
      - Go (Box 67, Folder 464)
      - Grace (Box 68, Folder 465)
      - Graduate School Office (Box 68, Folder 466 - 467)
      - Grah -Gu (Box 68, Folder 468)
      - H -Hart (Box 69, Folder 469)
      - Hartford Survey (Box 69, Folder 470)
      - Harv -Hen (Box 69, Folder 471)
      - Hers -Hes (Box 69, Folder 472)
      - HI (Box 69, Folder 473)
      - Hill, Clyde H. (Box 69, Folder 474)
      - Ho -Hos (Box 70, Folder 475)
      - Hou -Hoy (Box 70, Folder 476)
      - Hu -Hy (Box 70, Folder 477)
      - I (Box 70, Folder 478)
      - J -Jo (Box 70, Folder 479)
      - Ju (Box 70, Folder 480)
      - K -Kei (Box 70, Folder 481)
      - Kel -Kip (Box 71, Folder 482)
      - Kir -Kw (Box 71, Folder 483)
      - L -Lam (Box 71, Folder 484)
      - Lan -Lei (Box 71, Folder 485)
      - Lectures to Graduate (Box 71, Folder 486)
      - Lem -Li (Box 72, Folder 487)
      - Library (Box 72, Folder 488)
      - Loram, Charles T. (Box 72, Folder 489)
      - Lo (Box 72, Folder 490)
      - M -Mac (Box 72, Folder 491)
      - M -Mac (Box 72, Folder 492)
      - Mag -Mar (Box 73, Folder 493)
      - Mas -May May, Mark A. (Box 73, Folder 494 - 495)
      - Me -Mi (Box 73, Folder 496)
      - Mo -Mor (Box 73, Folder 497)
      - Mos -My (Box 73, Folder 498)
      - N -Ni (Box 74, Folder 499)
      - New London Junior College (Box 74, Folder 500)
      - New London Survey (Box 74, Folder 501)
      - Nl -Ny (Box 74, Folder 502)
      - October Conference (Box 74, Folder 503 - 504)
      - Oa -Ox (Box 74, Folder 505)
      - P -Phi (Box 75, Folder 506)
      - Parkhurst, Helen (Box 75, Folder 507)
      - Peat -Ph (Box 75, Folder 508)
      - Pillsbury, Howard PI -Pren (Box 75, Folder 509 - 510)
      - Pres -Pu (Box 75, Folder 511)
      - Progressive Education Association (Box 76, Folder 512)
      - Progressive Education Association (Box 76, Folder 513 - 515)
      - Provost's Office (Box 76, Folder 516 - 517)
      - Q R (Box 77, Folder 518 - 519)
      - Ri -Roo (Box 77, Folder 520)
      - Rop -Ry (Box 77, Folder 521)
      - S -Sch (Box 77, Folder 522)
      - Sco -Seo (Box 78, Folder 523)
      - Sep -Sh (Box 78, Folder 524)
      - Social Program of the department (Box 78, Folder 525)
      - Si -Sm (Box 78, Folder 526)
      - Sn -Sp (Box 78, Folder 527)
      - Spaulding, Frank E: Testimonial volume (Box 79, Folder 528 - 529)
      - St -Sto (Box 79, Folder 530)
      - State Department of Education (Box 79, Folder 531)
      - State Laws and Reports (Box 79, Folder 532)
      - Str -Sy (Box 80, Folder 533)
      - T -Thorn (Box 80, Folder 534)
      - Thor -Ty (Box 80, Folder 535)
      - Treasurer's Office (Box 80, Folder 536)
      - Treasurer's Office (Box 81, Folder 537 - 538)
      - U -V (Box 81, Folder 539)
      - United States Office of Education (Box 81, Folder 540)
      - Veterans' file (Box 81, Folder 541)
      - War Council Education Committee: memorandum (Box 81, Folder 542)
      - W-Ware (Box 81, Folder 543)
      - Warr -Well (Box 82, Folder 544)
      - X - Y -Z (Box 82, Folder 547)
    - Registrar's -Files, 1950-1953
      - 1950-1952 (Box 83, Folder 548 - 551)
      - 1950-1952 (Box 84, Folder 552 - 554)
      - 1952-1953 (Box 85, Folder 555 - 557)
    - Clyde Hill Files, 1950-1954
      - Appointment file (Box 86, Folder 558 - 559)
      - Child development card list (Box 86, Folder 560)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 86, Folder 561 - 562)
      - President's Committee (Box 86, Folder 563)
  - FACULTY MEETING MINUTES, 1926-1957; Series II
    - 1926-1933 (Box 87, Folder 1 - 4)
    - 1934-1957 (Box 88, Folder 5 - 9)
  - SEMINARS, LECTURES, CONFERENCES, COURSES, AND GRADES, REPORTS, 1905-1953; Series III
    - Applications for teaching assistance, 1945-1952 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, memoranda, 1936-1951 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Courses taken, record of, 1931-1934 (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Courses and grades: card list, 1905-1907 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Lists, miscellaneous, 1921-1951 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Publications: bulletins, summer conferences and sessions, 1930-1953 (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Summer seminar records, 1931-1933 (Box 91, Folder 7 - 9)
    - Summer seminar records, 1932-1933 (Box 92, Folder 10 - 12)
    - Teaching appointments sample forms, Undated (Box 92, Folder 13)
  - PRINTED MATERIAL, 1926-1958; Series IV
    - Stockbridge Survey, 1952 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Yale Bulletin, 1926-1958 (Box 93–94)
- Records of the Yale-Fairfield Study on elementary education, 1954-1960; Accession 1979-A-005
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2036
  - Daily Activity Records: Forms on which teachers list their activities and duties of each day and comments on their students., 1954-1960 (Box 1)
  - Daily Activity Records, 1954-1960 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Folders:, 1954-1960
    - "Nine folders on teachers participating in the Study on Scholarhip" (Box 3)
    - Reports on Teaching Fellows: (Box 3)
    - Achievement Test Results. (Box 3)
    - Evaluations, Intern Reports, Principal Reports (Box 3)
  - More Data on Teachers:, 1954-1960
    - Observation Sheets (Box 4)
    - Classroom Photographs (Box 4)
  - Financial Reports (1 folder), 1955-1960 (Box 4)
  - Executive Committee Minutes (1 folder), 1954-1959 (Box 4)
  - Executive Committee: Lists, Meetings, 1954-1960 (Box 5)
  - Finances: Applications, Budgets, Reports, Invoices, 1954-1960 (Box 5)